<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Social Bookmarks | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/social-bookmarks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:47:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delicious!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/01/18/delicious/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-18T06:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/01/18/delicious</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using tag|Connect (an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelink">Intelink</a> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_bookmarking">social bookmarking</a> service) at work, and have come to rely on it for link sharing and discovery. As a result, I began using <a href="http://del.icio.us/">del.icio.us</a> to mark places that I discover at home that might be of interest at work and visa-versa. I&rsquo;ve been using del.icio.us for over a year now, but have just now imported all my bookmarks from <a href="http://www.apple.com/safari">Safari</a>.</p>

<p>As a result, I now have a large number of bookmarks (the number jumped from 34 to 338), most of which are not shared (that seems to be how imported bookmarks are handled). I&rsquo;m now in the slow process of discovering what bookmarks I&rsquo;ve not used in a long time or were provided on my computer and of editing and sharing them&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Things I Want From Google]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/three-things-i-want-from-google/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-10T04:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/three-things-i-want-from-google</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A Single Identity</p>

<pre><code>I use some [Google](http://www.google.com/) services: [Blogger](http://www.blogger.com/), [History](http://www.google.com/history/), [Gmail](http://mail.google.com/), [Picasa](http://picasaweb.google.com/), [Reader](http://reader.google.com/), etc... and have accounts with a few other services. Although all these services share authentication and account information (which is as it should be), they do not share profiles, my name, my photograph, and I just want to be able to add details to my identity, change my photograph once, in any Google service, and have it change throughout the entire set of Google services.
</code></pre>

<p>Social Bookmarks</p>

<pre><code>I want the Google Bookmarks to be social in the same manner that [del.icio.us](http://del.icio.us/) or [Intelink Bookmarks](https://www.intelink.gov/bookmarks/) are.
</code></pre>

<p>Common Labels</p>

<pre><code>The Google services all support labeling (aka tagging) items, but seem to store the label sets privately within the service. When I label an item in Reader, I would like to be able to see that label when I am writing about it in Blogger, see what I have bookmarked with that label, etc.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
