<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Google | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/google/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:47:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanning Sync]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/16/spanning-sync/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-16T06:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/16/spanning-sync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://spanningsync.com/?r=8KYFFP"><img src="http://spanningsync.com/s5m5-badge_150x150.gif" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I use S<a href="http://spanningsync.com/?r=8KYFFP">panning Sync</a> to synchronize the address book and calendars on my Macs with my <a href="http://www.google.com/accounts">Google accounts</a> (yes, that&rsquo;s plural &ndash; I have one Google account, and one account at a <a href="http://www.google.com/apps/">Google Apps</a> site). It has been working great, allowing me to use my <a href="http://www.apple.com/imac">iMac</a> as the central hub by which everything else just stays in sync.</p>

<p>However, it is not free software, and being a heavy user of GNOME and other open source software projects, I spent some time shopping around for a free solution that performed as well as this, as easily as this, and just failed to find one. It&rsquo;s the first software purchase that I have made other than Mac OS X in a long time, and I think its been worth it.</p>

<p>Spanning Sync recently (a few months ago actually) began encouraging users to advertise the software by offering a discount to both the referred-to user and the referring user.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spam Yourself!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/18/spam-yourself/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-18T04:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/18/spam-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had once signed up for Google News alerts on a particular subject matter, and later cancelled the email alerts and switched to an RSS feed. I have finally cancelled the feed as well. I realized that I was spamming myself. It was interesting to see just how heavily duplicated a single article is, but not anymore.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacPorts Search]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/06/07/macports-search/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-07T04:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/06/07/macports-search</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month, I created a <a href="http://www.google.com/coop/cse?cx=011837386708472035020:5lqtx6zp3qw">Google Custom Search</a> of the <a href="http://www.macports.org/">MacPorts</a> websites: the project home, the  guide, the wiki, the tickets database, and the source code browser.</p>

<p>I had suggested using it within the MacPorts sites to the project managers, but have not heard any response one way or other, so here it is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Applications]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/01/06/google-applications/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-06T06:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/01/06/google-applications</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/01/currentstate.png"><img src="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/01/currentstate.png?w=300" alt="" /></a><a href="http://google.com/">Google</a> applications on <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx">Mac OS X</a> are installed by default either in the /Applications folder or a subfolder of /Applications (see the current state to the right).</p>

<p>I have every Google application installed:</p>

<p><a href="http://desktop.google.com/mac/">Google Desktop</a></p>

<pre><code>Its actually two applications, Google Desktop (a search tool integrating searches on the computer and the internet) and Google Gadgets (allowing widgets that work on the google.com pages to be displayed in the Dashboard) installed in the folder /Applications/Google Desktop.
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://earth.google.com/">Google Earth</a></p>

<pre><code>Its installed in /Applications. Unlike most of the Google applications, it is a complex application in its own right.
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://toolbar.google.com/gmail-helper/notifier_mac.html">Google Notifier</a></p>

<pre><code>This application places notifiers for GMail and the Google Calendar in the menu bar, and once running is accessed exclusively through the menu bar. Once a user decides to use it, it can be set to automatically start when the user logs in through its preferences window.
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://sketchup.google.com/">Google Sketchup</a></p>

<pre><code>This is a modeling application. For some reason it is installed in a versioned folder that contains nothing but the application.
</code></pre>

<p>Google Updater</p>

<pre><code>The tool that manages all of the Google applications. This tool installs, updates, and removes the other Google applications.
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://picasa.google.com/web/mac_tools.html">Picasa Web Albums Uploader</a></p>

<pre><code>An application for importing photos into the [Picasa web albums](http://picasaweb.google.com/). I use the [iPhoto](http://www.apple.com/iphoto) plugin that it installs. (The application is not shown in the listings.)
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/01/desiredstate2.png"><img src="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/01/desiredstate2.png?w=300" alt="" /></a> I want the Google Updater to install all of the applications that run as services on the computer, or are utilities for maintaining the computer, in the folder /Applications/Google Applications (or some similar name).</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know if this just some irritation of mine that I have too many applications on my computer or not, but I just don&rsquo;t like the current state of affairs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Things I Want From Google]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/three-things-i-want-from-google/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-10T04:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/three-things-i-want-from-google</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A Single Identity</p>

<pre><code>I use some [Google](http://www.google.com/) services: [Blogger](http://www.blogger.com/), [History](http://www.google.com/history/), [Gmail](http://mail.google.com/), [Picasa](http://picasaweb.google.com/), [Reader](http://reader.google.com/), etc... and have accounts with a few other services. Although all these services share authentication and account information (which is as it should be), they do not share profiles, my name, my photograph, and I just want to be able to add details to my identity, change my photograph once, in any Google service, and have it change throughout the entire set of Google services.
</code></pre>

<p>Social Bookmarks</p>

<pre><code>I want the Google Bookmarks to be social in the same manner that [del.icio.us](http://del.icio.us/) or [Intelink Bookmarks](https://www.intelink.gov/bookmarks/) are.
</code></pre>

<p>Common Labels</p>

<pre><code>The Google services all support labeling (aka tagging) items, but seem to store the label sets privately within the service. When I label an item in Reader, I would like to be able to see that label when I am writing about it in Blogger, see what I have bookmarked with that label, etc.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
