<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: MySpace | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/myspace/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-22T06:01:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[@^#%&*^% MySpace!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/04/30/myspace/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-30T05:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/04/30/myspace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I hate <a href="http://www.myspace.com">MySpace</a>. But not enough to be passionate about it. Just enough to do what I have to to minimally maintain a site that points people to tools that I do use.</p>

<p>About a year ago, I was trying to lookup an old classmate who I knew to be a MySpace user. So I created a MySpace account so I could get an email address. Or tried to create an account. The MySpace software just crapped out with meaningless error message halfway through the initial registration process, leaving me with an account that exists, but can&rsquo;t be logged into. MySpace&rsquo;s technical support people were all like totally unhelpful, spitting out canned messages that seemed like they matched keywords describing my problem.</p>

<p>So I then created a second MySpace account, using a different email address that I had access to, and it worked, and I got the email addresses I wanted and forgot about it.</p>

<p>Until last week, when a young soldier I work with was all like &ldquo;You need to try this MySpace thing&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>And then the next day (Thursday or Friday, I forget which) was all like &ldquo;You need to work on your profile&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>So this weekend I worked on my profile.</p>

<p>I swear, for about two days after I edited profile information (relationship?, education?) from &ldquo;No Answer&rdquo; to &ldquo;Married&rdquo; and &ldquo;College Graduate&rdquo; every add was for single women looking for fast and loose sexual relationships (I&rsquo;m guessing these were targetted to the fact that I&rsquo;m male) and I keep getting &ldquo;Freind requests&rdquo; from (apparently) young women who like sex and to party and nude photography and a profile that is a big link I guess is to some paid sex site.</p>

<p>Grrr&hellip;..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
