<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:43:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Jenkins Node Daemon on OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2012/11/25/a-jenkins-node-daemon-on-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T12:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2012/11/25/a-jenkins-node-daemon-on-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Update:</strong> Use the <a href="https://github.com/rhwood/jenkins-slave-osx">Jenkins Slave for OS X</a> instead. It&rsquo;s based on these gists and has the benefit of being maintained.</p>

<p>I have been using <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org">Jenkins</a> for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration">continuous integration</a> (CI) with some Java-based projects, and recently setup Jenkins for CI for a OS X application. For the Java-based projects, running Jenkins on a <a href="http://www.linode.com/?r=b70e8c306162d25af8a47771c9226cdedf99e94a">Linode</a> works well, but the Linode-based Jenkins instance cannot build iOS or OS X applications.</p>

<p>Its easy to setup Jenkins to support <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Distributed+builds">distributed builds</a> with a OS X system as a slave, provided the master can initiate SSH communications to the slave. If, like me, your Jenkins master cannot initiate a connection with your slave (which is my desktop iMac), it is still trivial to configure the slave to use <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Distributed+builds#Distributedbuilds-LaunchslaveagentviaJavaWebStart">Java Web Start</a> (JNLP).</p>

<p>I generally followed <a href="http://eclipsesource.com/blogs/author/hstaudacher/">Holger Staudacher&rsquo;s</a> <a href="http://eclipsesource.com/blogs/2012/06/01/ups-and-downs-with-continuous-integration-for-ios-apps-jenkins-xcode-cobertura-and-testflight/">post on the subject</a>. However, he was frustrated by his inability to configure his Mac to automatically start the JNLP connection.</p>

<p>The following script launches the Jenkins slave service via Java Web Start after downloading the slave.jar file (thereby ensuring that the slave.jar is always the current version):</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4136130.js?file=slave.jnlp.sh'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>#!/bin/bash

JENKINS_SLAVE=`hostname -s | tr '[:upper:]' '[:lower:]'`
JENKINS_MASTER=http://jenkins
JENKINS_PORT=''

if [ -f /etc/jenkins.node.conf ]; then
    source /etc/jenkins.node.conf
fi

while [ $# -gt 0 ]; do
        case $1 in
                --node=*)
                        JENKINS_SLAVE=${1#*=}
                        ;;
                --master=*)
                        JENKINS_MASTER=${1#*=}
                        ;;
                --jnlp-port=*)
                        JENKINS_PORT=&quot;:${1#*=}&quot;
                        ;;
        esac
        shift
done

echo &quot;Getting slave.jar from ${JENKINS_MASTER}&quot;
RESULT=-1
while [ $RESULT -ne 0 ]; do
        curl --url ${JENKINS_MASTER}/jnlpJars/slave.jar -o /var/lib/jenkins/slave.jar
        RESULT=$?
        if [ $RESULT -ne 0 ]; then
                sleep 10
        fi
done
JENKINS_JNLP_URL=${JENKINS_MASTER}${JENKINS_PORT}/computer/${JENKINS_SLAVE}/slave-agent.jnlp
echo &quot;Launching slave process at ${JENKINS_JNLP_URL}&quot;
java -jar /var/lib/jenkins/slave.jar -jnlpUrl ${JENKINS_JNLP_URL}
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>Launchd (the OS X launch manager) can launch this file using the following property list:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4136130.js?file=org.jenkins-ci.slave.jnlp.plist'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;!DOCTYPE plist PUBLIC &quot;-/Apple/DTD PLIST 1.0/EN&quot; &quot;http:/www.apple.com/DTDs/PropertyList-1.0.dtd&quot;&gt;
&lt;plist version=&quot;1.0&quot;&gt;
&lt;dict&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;Label&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;string&gt;org.jenkins-ci.slave.jnlp&lt;/string&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;ProgramArguments&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;array&gt;
        &lt;string&gt;/var/lib/jenkins/slave.jnlp.sh&lt;/string&gt;
        &lt;string&gt;--master=http://jenkins.example.com&lt;/string&gt;
    &lt;/array&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;KeepAlive&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;true/&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;RunAtLoad&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;true/&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;UserName&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;string&gt;jenkins&lt;/string&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;WorkingDirectory&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;string&gt;/var/lib/jenkins&lt;/string&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;StandardInPath&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;string&gt;/dev/null&lt;/string&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;StandardErrorPath&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;string&gt;/var/log/jenkins/jenkins.log&lt;/string&gt;
    &lt;key&gt;StandardOutPath&lt;/key&gt;
    &lt;string&gt;/var/log/jenkins/jenkins.log&lt;/string&gt;
&lt;/dict&gt;
&lt;/plist&gt;</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>I have a simple script that can install these files for use by the user <em>jenkins</em>:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/4136130.js?file=install.sh'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>#!/bin/sh
# create jenkins group
NEXT_GID=$((`dscl /Local/Default list /Groups gid | awk '{ print $2 }' | sort -n | grep -v ^[5-9] | tail -n1` + 1))
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Groups/jenkins
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Groups/jenkins PrimaryGroupID $NEXT_GID
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Groups/jenkins Password \*
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Groups/jenkins RealName 'Jenkins Node Service'
# create jenkins user
NEXT_UID=$((`dscl /Local/Default list /Users uid | awk '{ print $2 }' | sort -n | grep -v ^[5-9] | tail -n1` + 1))
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Users/jenkins
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Users/jenkins UniqueID $NEXT_UID
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Users/jenkins PrimaryGroupID $NEXT_GID
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Users/jenkins UserShell /usr/bin/false
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Users/jenkins NFSHomeDirectory /var/lib/jenkins
sudo dscl /Local/Default create /Users/jenkins Password \*
sudo dseditgroup -o edit -a jenkins -t user jenkins
# download the LaunchDaemon
sudo curl --url https://raw.github.com/gist/4136130/d3c9d7275ce78e050d8594037a2d509652a766e5/org.jenkins-ci.slave.jnlp.plist -o /Library/LaunchDaemons/org.jenkins-ci.slave.jnlp.plist
# create the jenkins home dir
sudo mkdir /var/lib/jenkins
# download the jenkins JNLP slave script
sudo curl --url https://raw.github.com/gist/4136130/2553c4cec9bc7ed5557359a22c6c1b61028afa40/slave.jnlp.sh -o /var/lib/jenkins/slave.jnlp.sh
sudo chown -R jenkins:wheel /var/lib/jenkins
sudo chmod 755 /var/lib/jenkins/slave.jnlp.sh
# create a logging space
sudo mkdir /var/log/jenkins
sudo chown jenkins:wheel /var/log/jenkins
# remember to edit the LaunchDaemon
echo &quot;IMPORTANT:&quot;
echo &quot;edit /Library/LaunchDaemons/org.jenkins-ci.slave.jnlp.plist to use the correct master&quot;</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>It can be run by copying the following command into a Terminal window:</p>

<pre><code>bash &lt;(curl -L https://raw.github.com/gist/4136130/81ee34ac6dd01e4f81e9b69650041c64f2e09678/install.sh)
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing a Throwaway App]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2011/08/28/writing-a-throwaway-app/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-28T15:19:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2011/08/28/writing-a-throwaway-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I was mobilizing late last year (in mid-to-late December), I had an idea of an easy, simple app that I could write for the iPhone. It would serve a purpose both my wife and I had (tracking the length of my deployment in a single pie chart à la the <em>Deployment Donut</em> or <em>Donut of Misery</em>), and once written, I would not need to maintain it. It was a to be a <em>throwaway app</em>.</p>

<p>I think I first heard the term <em>throwaway app</em> on the <a href="http://ideveloper.tv/shows">MDN Show</a> in 2010. A throwaway app is an app that is written with comparatively little investment in the intention that it will require no maintenance or commitment, while possibly generating a little income. So I had this throwaway app that I submitted to Apple while sitting on an upper bunk in a 50-man tent over a sporadic wifi connection in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transit_Center_at_Manas">Manas</a>. If Apple approved it, I had a throwaway app, knew I could develop an app, and could contemplate writing other more complex apps that required commitment.</p>

<p>Well, maybe not. After Apple approved the app and I got it into the App Store (almost the day I arrived in theatre on my deployment), I quickly got a number of emails offering to review the app from questionable operations, and a week later got my first review.</p>

<p>One Star. Negative comment. The app disappointed. Additional reviews were equally negative.</p>

<p><strong>I had failed.</strong> I doubted that I could write an app. Even a simple one. Eventually I relaxed enough to think that I could recover from this, that I could fix the issues in the app, and at least get a positive comment about it.</p>

<p>In a few weeks, I managed to release the first update, which addressed not only the initial negative comments, but also a few issues I had noted over time and which managed to provide a revenue stream (an In-App Purchase that eliminated adds and allowed the app to display multiple pie charts).</p>

<p>I got positive reviews. And people actually upgraded the app—enough so that the app covered the costs of developing it (excepting my labor), and revenues from the app increase every month.</p>

<p>Since then I&rsquo;ve released two updates that address bugs. I am preparing an update to introduce some new features. Clearly the App is no longer a throwaway app<em>—</em>I am now committed to the app. Now if only I can figure out how to market it on the cheap&hellip;</p>

<p>Incidentally, the App in question is <a href="http://axsw.co/gdZJa6">Doing Time</a>, is currently well rated, and other than a support page for it, this is the first mention I&rsquo;ve made of it other than on the App Store itself. I deliberately attempted to avoid describing the app while writing this, since this essay is about a throwaway app that no longer exists, since it receiving active maintenance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Matters Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/12/14/what-matters-now/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-14T20:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/12/14/what-matters-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2009/12/what-matters-now-get-the-free-ebook.html">collection of short essays</a> has got me thinking about life again and living it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Diego]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/12/13/san-diego/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-13T22:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/12/13/san-diego</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I fell in love with San Diego and California and Los Angeles all over again and again and again while on a business trip out to San Diego. First I fell in love with San Diego driving up the 163 towards Escondido from downtown, where I was staying in admittedly one of the cheaper feeling hotels I&rsquo;ve been in and definitely the cheapest feeling Hampton Inn I&rsquo;ve been in.</p>

<p>163 starts in downtown, on the wrong side of a hill from the coast and immediately dives through a narrow valley crossed by high bridges and I fell in love that morning and that evening I walked through the residential area between downtown and the airport and fell in love again.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I was mostly reclusive, up too early on the phone with the home office, driving to the work site just after sun up and leaving the work site at sun down and did not enjoy the place&mdash;what the Hell&rsquo;s the point of visiting paradise if your going to be stuck indoors without windows all day. I made a wrong turn onto the 805 and fell in love again when it cut through a hill and then was suddenly soaring above a built-up valley in the early evening and was then back into the hills.</p>

<p>My brother, Chandler, lives in Los Angeles and I drove up to LA to see him, and on the I-5 the drive was lovely until I crested some hill (I don&rsquo;t recall where) and saw looming ahead, the smog of LA.</p>

<p><strong>Note: </strong>for some reason this sat as a draft for almost a year, and I forget what I wanted to write when I began writing it, so here it is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft's Killer Application]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/05/06/microsofts-killer-application/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-06T05:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/05/06/microsofts-killer-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s well&hellip;it&rsquo;s <em>Microsoft</em>.</p>

<p>Frequently I&rsquo;ll hear people refer to the product of a company with a single product (or a single predominant product or range of closely related products) by the company name (for example <a href="http://www.citrix.com/">Citrix</a> of <a href="http://www.vmware.com/">VMware</a>). But (mostly non-technical) people also seem to refer to Microsoft products as just being <em>Microsoft.</em></p>

<p>Not only does Microsoft not have a single product, Microsoft has a range of duplicative products&mdash;products which perform the same task but which do so in inconsistent and sometimes even incompatible manners: Outlook and Outlook Express/Windows Live Mail (mutually exclusive support for differing mail servers or services), Office and Works (differing file formats for the same task), Outlook and Windows Address Book/Windows Live Contacts.</p>

<p>But its all called <em>Microsoft</em> and I think its that confusion between products and what is in the Operating System and what is not that has benefited Microsoft and made it really difficult for Apple and the various Linux distributions to supplant it.</p>

<p>I know this is a rough idea, and I&rsquo;ll return to it, but I just wanted to say that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A letter to an old friend:]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/04/09/a-letter-to-an-old-friend/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-09T22:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/04/09/a-letter-to-an-old-friend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember being very angry at what I felt was an unnecessarily self congratulatory tone of <em>Unzipped</em>, the movie about Isaac Mizrahi. I remember that you seemed somewhat shocked by that.</p>

<p>I now know that I was wrong wrong wrong about that&mdash;celebrating one&rsquo;s life is, well, a celebration worth having; failing to celebrate one&rsquo;s life and one&rsquo;s feeling of accomplishment is a wrong thing to do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lonely Saxophones]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/03/30/lonely-saxophones/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-30T08:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/03/30/lonely-saxophones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember one summer at home&mdash;I think it was the summer of &lsquo;98&mdash;when a single lonely saxophone would play out over the roofs of the neighborhood in the evenings. It was one of the insanely beautiful moments that made Raleigh seem at so much more urbane and cosmopolitan than it seemed during the day.</p>

<p>In any event, yesterday was the first day of spring when doors and windows were flung open and people just stayed outdoors. Usually the music of balmy afternoons in my neighborhood is of a Mexican or Salvadorian flavor, and occasionally jazz or even classical music. Unfortunately this time it was abrasive sensationalist Hip-hop of the most banal and vulgar kind.</p>

<p>Somehow I managed to shutout the lyrics and think of that saxophone until the language was brought to my attention, and it kind of put a damper on the afternoon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[F-16s at night]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/03/22/f-16s-at-night/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-22T20:47:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/03/22/f-16s-at-night</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been at Shaw AFB for work for the week, and frequently hear fighter jets overhead. They are impressive little engines with wings and at night they look like the pilot is sitting on an open flame when they take off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MobileMe and Incompatible Browsers]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/12/08/mobileme-and-incompatible-browsers/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-08T05:10:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/12/08/mobileme-and-incompatible-browsers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had gotten used to using my <a href="http://idisk.me.com/">iDisk</a> to hold personal stuff that I need when I&rsquo;m at drills, but was surprised to see the following when attempting to get to it:<a href="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/12/me-on-ie.png"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/12/me-on-ie.png"><img src="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/12/me-on-ie.png?w=300" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>While it turns out that I can read the iDisk with <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/ie">Internet Explorer</a> , I did have to consult <a href="http://www.apple.com/">Apple</a> &rsquo;s <a href="http://www.apple.com/support/mobileme/">support site</a> to do so. Luckly, Apple is not so picky about how you can access that. Unfortunately, <a href="http://www.spreadfirefox.com/?q=affiliates&amp;id=118911&amp;t=45">Firefox</a> does not yet seem to be widely available on <a href="http://www.defenselink.mil/">DoD</a> computers on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NIPRNET">NIPRNET</a> yet, or I never would have noticed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading to Fedora 10]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/28/upgrading-to-fedora-10/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-28T05:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/28/upgrading-to-fedora-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday morning I upgraded my work laptop from Fedora 9 to <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/get-fedora">Fedora 10</a>. Other than a couple of issues outlined below, the experience seemed reasonable:</p>

<h4>Issues</h4>

<ul>
<li>The bootloader (grub) did not upgrade correctly, leaving me at a grub prompt when the computer started. Apparently this is a common issue. The fix was simple in my case:

<ol>
<li><code>root (hd0,1)</code></li>
<li><code>setup (hd0,1)</code></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.vmware.com/products/ws/">VMware Workstation</a> refused to heal from the upgrade. Usually VMware Workstation just heals itself after I update the kernel, but for some reason it refused to heal itself. Again a simple fix:</p>

<ol>
<li><code>rm /usr/lib/vmware/modules/binary</code></li>
<li><code>vmware modconfig --console --install-all</code></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Immediately after installing Fedora (on only the second day after its release) there were a ridiculous number of updates to be downloaded, so I basically the first thing I did with the system was let it download and install updates for three hours.</li>
</ul>


<h4>References</h4>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://tofu.org/drupal/node/69">Fedora 10 Upgrade Experience | tofu.org</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://geekdom.wesmo.com/2008/11/14/fedora-10-vmware-workstation-650/">Geekdom » Post Topic » Fedora 10 + VMware Workstation 6.5.0</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spanning Sync]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/16/spanning-sync/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-16T06:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/16/spanning-sync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://spanningsync.com/?r=8KYFFP"><img src="http://spanningsync.com/s5m5-badge_150x150.gif" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I use S<a href="http://spanningsync.com/?r=8KYFFP">panning Sync</a> to synchronize the address book and calendars on my Macs with my <a href="http://www.google.com/accounts">Google accounts</a> (yes, that&rsquo;s plural &ndash; I have one Google account, and one account at a <a href="http://www.google.com/apps/">Google Apps</a> site). It has been working great, allowing me to use my <a href="http://www.apple.com/imac">iMac</a> as the central hub by which everything else just stays in sync.</p>

<p>However, it is not free software, and being a heavy user of GNOME and other open source software projects, I spent some time shopping around for a free solution that performed as well as this, as easily as this, and just failed to find one. It&rsquo;s the first software purchase that I have made other than Mac OS X in a long time, and I think its been worth it.</p>

<p>Spanning Sync recently (a few months ago actually) began encouraging users to advertise the software by offering a discount to both the referred-to user and the referring user.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to tell if a computer is too old]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/09/21/how-to-tell-if-a-computer-is-too-old/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-21T16:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/09/21/how-to-tell-if-a-computer-is-too-old</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife: &ldquo;I have to email it to [the president of a local club]. Her computer is ancient. It is beige.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inbox Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/21/inbox-control/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-21T08:31:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/21/inbox-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using the <a href="http://www.43folders.com/izero">Inbox 0</a> system to manage my email at work for a couple of months. It&rsquo;s working out mostly, as I find that I sometimes let my Inbox grow again before cleaning it up, and I still have not gone completely though the DMZ folder to determine what needs to be archived and what doesn&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Prior to using Inbox 0 to manage the inbox, I had been using search filters to control my email, but still found that it wasn&rsquo;t working to well. When I received I forget what version of Mac OS X with really good search engines in the email, and then later got a <a href="http://mail.google.com/">Gmail</a> account, I began to use search folders, and it worked for a while, until the sheer volume of email overwhelmed it.</p>

<p>Also this never worked at work, since neither <a href="http://office.microsoft.com/outlook">Outlook</a> (2003) nor <a href="http://projects.gnome.org/evolution/">Evolution</a> seem to be good at filtering email or searching through inboxes, in my experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spam Yourself!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/18/spam-yourself/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-18T04:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/18/spam-yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had once signed up for Google News alerts on a particular subject matter, and later cancelled the email alerts and switched to an RSS feed. I have finally cancelled the feed as well. I realized that I was spamming myself. It was interesting to see just how heavily duplicated a single article is, but not anymore.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/shopping/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-17T12:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/shopping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went grocery shopping at <a href="http://www.safeway.com">Safeway</a> for the first time today. We regularly shop at <a href="http://www.shopbloom.com">Bloom</a>, in Herndon, a smaller grocery store. Chrysta and I made the decision that Bloom is not only likely to be less expensive for us to shop at, and that Bloom&rsquo;s <a href="http://shopbloom.com/AllAboutBloom/ScanningIsABreeze.aspx">personal scanners</a> are a compelling feature when shopping with small children. I&rsquo;ll still use Safeway when running small errands while picking up Augusta from preschool (its comfortably on the way by bicycle), but not for regular shopping.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 miles]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/20-miles/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-17T05:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/20-miles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I rode a little more than 20 miles on the <a href="http://www.nvrpa.org/parks/wod/index.php">Washington &amp; Old Dominion trail</a>. Isabella rode with me, and apparently slept most of the trip. This was my first 20 mile cycle ride in I-don&rsquo;t-know-how-long, at least 5 years, and much to my surprise, despite my not having warmed up before hand, I&rsquo;m not sore as a result.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workspace Switcher]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/14/workspace-switcher/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-14T08:19:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/14/workspace-switcher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why does the commercial application display its icon in the GNOME Workspace Switcher (even though it is not full screen), but the open source applications don&rsquo;t?</p>

<p><a href="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/08/screenshot.png"><img src="http://shyramblings.files.wordpress.com/2008/08/screenshot.png?w=109" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The applications open in the Switcher are from left-to-right:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Evolution (a GNOME project)</p></li>
<li><p>VMWare Workstation</p></li>
<li><p>Yelp (a GNOME project)</p></li>
<li><p>Firefox</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Afraid of risk]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/09/afraid-of-risk/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-09T10:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/09/afraid-of-risk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to be totally flexible in my life. It (my live, my future) was wide open, on some arid plains somewhere, full of beauty and possibility.</p>

<p>Now it feels like my life is in Brazil&mdash;the movie, not the country&mdash;stuck in long corridors, filled with locked doors. My fear of taking any risks with my life, my kid&rsquo;s lives, and Chrysta&rsquo;s life, is the lock which bars me from opening any of these doors.</p>

<p>I feel that even posting this message is attacking that fear, and can only hope that this gives me the strength to push farther and harder (without, of course, taking excessive risks).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off the Wall]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/02/off-the-wall/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-02T19:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/02/off-the-wall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://music.barnesandnoble.com/Off-the-Wall/Michael-Jackson/e/074646607022/?itm=1&amp;afsrc=1&amp;lkid=J25893202&amp;pubid=K117976&amp;byo=1"><img src="http://clickserve.cc-dt.com/link/banner?lid=41000000025893202" alt="" /></a> I recently heard a song on the radio that made me realize that my music collection was missing a critical album: Michael Jackson&rsquo;s <strong>Off the Wall</strong>. It&rsquo;s not my first iTunes purchase, but it&rsquo;s my first in a long time. I also spent a few hours simply feeding CDs to my computer to add to my iTunes library.
<a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=alo5c2JFv50&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http%253A%252F%252Fphobos.apple.com%252FWebObjects%252FMZStore.woa%252Fwa%252FviewAlbum%253Fi%253D186166433%2526id%253D186166282%2526s%253D143441%2526partnerId%253D30"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://click.linksynergy.com/fs-bin/stat?id=alo5c2JFv50&amp;offerid=146261&amp;type=3&amp;subid=0&amp;tmpid=1826&amp;RD_PARM1=http%253A%252F%252Fphobos.apple.com%252FWebObjects%252FMZStore.woa%252Fwa%252FviewAlbum%253Fi%253D186166433%2526id%253D186166282%2526s%253D143441%2526partnerId%253D30"><img src="http://ax.phobos.apple.com.edgesuite.net/images/badgeitunes61x15dark.gif" alt="Michael Jackson - Off the Wall" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gimp on Mac OS X without X11 from MacPorts Redux]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/06/09/gimp-on-mac-os-x-without-x11-from-macports-redux/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-09T04:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/06/09/gimp-on-mac-os-x-without-x11-from-macports-redux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago, I wrote about using <a href="http://www.gimp.org/">Gimp</a> on <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx">Mac OS X</a> without <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X11">X11</a> from <a href="http://www.macports.org/">MacPorts</a>. Since then I&rsquo;ve upgraded my systems to Mac OS X Leopard (version 10.5), and experienced the <a href="http://trac.macports.org/ticket/15209">font rendering problem</a> myself. That problem is now fixed.</p>

<p>If you need to get an existing installation of gimp working, do the following:</p>

<pre><code>sudo port sync
sudo port upgrade cairo
sudo port -f uninstall pango
sudo port clean --all pango
sudo port install pango +no_x11
</code></pre>

<p>If you are installing Gimp for the first time, the following should work:</p>

<pre><code>sudo port clean --all
sudo port install cairo +quartz +no_x11
sudo port install poppler +quartz
sudo port install gail +quartz
sudo port install gimp2
sudo port install gimp +quartz
</code></pre>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Check out the MacPorts users mailing lists (<a href="http://lists.macosforge.org/mailman/listinfo/macports-users/">http://lists.macosforge.org/mailman/listinfo/macports-users/</a>) and trac database (<a href="http://trac.macports.org">http://trac.macports.org</a>) for assistance if this does not work for you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
