<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Photos | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/photos/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:43:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redoing the Living Room]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/redoing-the-living-room/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-10T05:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/redoing-the-living-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend, we rearranged the common area (a combined living room/dining room) to not block off the living room as a separate room. It created the impression of significantly more space, gave us impetus to hang all of the artwork that Denis and Ingrid brought with them last time they visited, and makes the apartment feel more like a home and less like a transient barracks. There are <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/RedoingTheLivingRoom">some photos</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Habits, Bad or Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/06/03/habits-bad-or-good/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-03T06:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/06/03/habits-bad-or-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/LazyFilmCartridge"><img src="http://lh5.google.com/image/randall.h.wood/RmKX7tCx5RE/AAAAAAAAAqY/siqgCJoti4E/s160-c/LazyFilmCartridge.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/LazyFilmCartridge">Lazy Film Cartridge</a></p>

<p>Way back when in late 2003, Kathy, my mother-in-law, bought us a digital camera so that we could send her pictures of her grandchild, due to be born in April 2004. We took the camera on a trip to visit Chrysta&rsquo;s father in December 2003 in Kansas City. I think that all of 6 photos survive from that trip. They are on the memory card that came with the camera, which we found recently. It is a 32MB card (we use a 512MB one now). There are a couple of pictures from Alexandria from about that time as well a set of very recent (as in last week) photos of our girls.</p>

<p>That the photos that survive from that trip, with the exception of a single photo of Sam, are from Chicago where we had a layover or from the train on that same day is indicitive of our <strong>habit</strong>.</p>

<p>The <em>habit</em> is the habit of forgetting that we have the (or a) camera. I like to say that I am too busy living life to document it, but sometimes wonder if I am simply justifying the <em>habit</em>. I do know that Denis (my father) taught both explicitly and by example that I was not to honor others attempts to document their lives with video by not worrying about walking between him and his subject, but was to honor the still photographer&rsquo;s attempts to take a photo by not walking in between him and his subject. I also hate posing for photographs and prefer photographs that depict people just living. Chrysta just does not like being photographed&hellip;</p>

<p>BTW, the photo album is so named simply because the memory stick has sat in a drawer for a while.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photos from this weekend]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/04/22/photos-from-this-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-22T14:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/04/22/photos-from-this-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/DogwoodFestival2007"><img src="http://lh5.google.com/image/randall.h.wood/RiupVkB8hvE/AAAAAAAAAVs/aJaY5_j96lU/s160-c/DogwoodFestival2007.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/DogwoodFestival2007">Dogwood Festival 2007</a></p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/EnergeticExcitement"><img src="http://lh3.google.com/image/randall.h.wood/RiukzEB8g3E/AAAAAAAAAP4/5IL1mKIwkW4/s160-c/EnergeticExcitement.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/EnergeticExcitement">Energetic Excitement</a></p>

<p>I took a lot of photographs this weekend, just to discover that the camera I was using was set in manual mode and therefore emulating using ISO 50 film for some damned reason. So almost all the photos are slightly blurry and in some cases it seems to work very well.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/DogwoodFestival2007">first album</a> is from the Carnival for the <a href="http://dogwoodfestival.org">Charlottesville Dogwood Festival</a> held at <a href="http://www.charlottesville.org/Index.aspx?page=367">McIntire Park</a>.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/EnergeticExcitement">second album</a> is from playing in Washington Park this morning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Old Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/04/22/old-photos/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-22T14:51:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/04/22/old-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/OurWedding"><img src="http://lh3.google.com/image/randall.h.wood/RiushEB8ieE/AAAAAAAAAkM/FWYfWgGteeE/s160-c/OurWedding.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/OurWedding">Our Wedding</a></p>

<p>Today I uploaded the official photos from our wedding. These photos are about 6 years old now, but I am moving them from my <a href="http://www.mac.com">.Mac</a> account to <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com">Picasa Web Albums</a> to free space up from my remote backups and to consolidate all my public photos in one place.</p>

<p>Incidentally, I have more than one <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood">public gallery</a> at Picasa.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
