<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Family | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:43:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[San Diego]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/12/13/san-diego/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-13T22:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/12/13/san-diego</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I fell in love with San Diego and California and Los Angeles all over again and again and again while on a business trip out to San Diego. First I fell in love with San Diego driving up the 163 towards Escondido from downtown, where I was staying in admittedly one of the cheaper feeling hotels I&rsquo;ve been in and definitely the cheapest feeling Hampton Inn I&rsquo;ve been in.</p>

<p>163 starts in downtown, on the wrong side of a hill from the coast and immediately dives through a narrow valley crossed by high bridges and I fell in love that morning and that evening I walked through the residential area between downtown and the airport and fell in love again.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I was mostly reclusive, up too early on the phone with the home office, driving to the work site just after sun up and leaving the work site at sun down and did not enjoy the place&mdash;what the Hell&rsquo;s the point of visiting paradise if your going to be stuck indoors without windows all day. I made a wrong turn onto the 805 and fell in love again when it cut through a hill and then was suddenly soaring above a built-up valley in the early evening and was then back into the hills.</p>

<p>My brother, Chandler, lives in Los Angeles and I drove up to LA to see him, and on the I-5 the drive was lovely until I crested some hill (I don&rsquo;t recall where) and saw looming ahead, the smog of LA.</p>

<p><strong>Note: </strong>for some reason this sat as a draft for almost a year, and I forget what I wanted to write when I began writing it, so here it is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/shopping/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-17T12:52:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/shopping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went grocery shopping at <a href="http://www.safeway.com">Safeway</a> for the first time today. We regularly shop at <a href="http://www.shopbloom.com">Bloom</a>, in Herndon, a smaller grocery store. Chrysta and I made the decision that Bloom is not only likely to be less expensive for us to shop at, and that Bloom&rsquo;s <a href="http://shopbloom.com/AllAboutBloom/ScanningIsABreeze.aspx">personal scanners</a> are a compelling feature when shopping with small children. I&rsquo;ll still use Safeway when running small errands while picking up Augusta from preschool (its comfortably on the way by bicycle), but not for regular shopping.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 miles]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/20-miles/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-17T05:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/17/20-miles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I rode a little more than 20 miles on the <a href="http://www.nvrpa.org/parks/wod/index.php">Washington &amp; Old Dominion trail</a>. Isabella rode with me, and apparently slept most of the trip. This was my first 20 mile cycle ride in I-don&rsquo;t-know-how-long, at least 5 years, and much to my surprise, despite my not having warmed up before hand, I&rsquo;m not sore as a result.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Afraid of risk]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/09/afraid-of-risk/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-09T10:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/08/09/afraid-of-risk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to be totally flexible in my life. It (my live, my future) was wide open, on some arid plains somewhere, full of beauty and possibility.</p>

<p>Now it feels like my life is in Brazil&mdash;the movie, not the country&mdash;stuck in long corridors, filled with locked doors. My fear of taking any risks with my life, my kid&rsquo;s lives, and Chrysta&rsquo;s life, is the lock which bars me from opening any of these doors.</p>

<p>I feel that even posting this message is attacking that fear, and can only hope that this gives me the strength to push farther and harder (without, of course, taking excessive risks).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Streetcar!]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/11/23/streetcar/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-23T07:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/11/23/streetcar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/p/851670FD59236321">http://www.youtube.com/p/851670FD59236321</a></p>

<p>Jasper, my grandfather, made this movie way back when about the streetcars in Cleveland, Ohio. Here it is, in two parts, along with a lecture his son, Christopher (an uncle of mine) gave about the movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
