<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: eSite | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/esite/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:43:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[eSite]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2005/12/09/esite-2/"/>
    <updated>2005-12-09T22:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2005/12/09/esite-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://esite.sf.net">eSite</a> is a tool for handling static web content. It basically allows for complex looking sites and some simple scripting (to, say, generate an index or complex tables based on external data that change infrequently, but drastically enough that hand maintenance is a pain) before pushing the static content to a server. eSite requires <a href="http://www.php.net">PHP</a> on the system it runs on.</p>

<p>I finally got eSite into CVS on Sourceforge, so others can play with it. That&rsquo;s the real news here.</p>

<p>eSite is used to generate the templates for this blog, and a couple of pages that track, in a semi-automated way, some other information as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[eSite]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2005/09/08/esite/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-08T05:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2005/09/08/esite</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had been maintaining my site with a combination of online tools (<a href="http://Blogger.com">Blogger</a> mostly, <a href="http://www.mac.com">.Mac</a>, and a bunch of google searches), some tools I installed via <a href="http://darwinports.opendarwin.org">Darwinports</a> (bluefish, drivel, and gedit), and a set of PHP, shell, and Makefile scripts that I built up over time.</p>

<p>Well, that is changing.</p>

<p>I have rewritten some of the scripts into a general purpose tool to maintain static  websites called <a href="http://esite.sourceforge.net">eSite</a>, as in &ldquo;easy site.&rdquo; The tool turned out to be a little more complex than expected and a little more flexible than expected and so I documented it and squated on a dead SourceForge project to share it with others.</p>

<p>The tool has replaced all but one script that I had used previously to maintain the sites. And it has generated a second site to maintain as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
