<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Upgrade | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/upgrade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:47:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading to Fedora 10]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/28/upgrading-to-fedora-10/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-28T05:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/11/28/upgrading-to-fedora-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday morning I upgraded my work laptop from Fedora 9 to <a href="http://fedoraproject.org/get-fedora">Fedora 10</a>. Other than a couple of issues outlined below, the experience seemed reasonable:</p>

<h4>Issues</h4>

<ul>
<li>The bootloader (grub) did not upgrade correctly, leaving me at a grub prompt when the computer started. Apparently this is a common issue. The fix was simple in my case:

<ol>
<li><code>root (hd0,1)</code></li>
<li><code>setup (hd0,1)</code></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.vmware.com/products/ws/">VMware Workstation</a> refused to heal from the upgrade. Usually VMware Workstation just heals itself after I update the kernel, but for some reason it refused to heal itself. Again a simple fix:</p>

<ol>
<li><code>rm /usr/lib/vmware/modules/binary</code></li>
<li><code>vmware modconfig --console --install-all</code></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Immediately after installing Fedora (on only the second day after its release) there were a ridiculous number of updates to be downloaded, so I basically the first thing I did with the system was let it download and install updates for three hours.</li>
</ul>


<h4>References</h4>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://tofu.org/drupal/node/69">Fedora 10 Upgrade Experience | tofu.org</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://geekdom.wesmo.com/2008/11/14/fedora-10-vmware-workstation-650/">Geekdom » Post Topic » Fedora 10 + VMware Workstation 6.5.0</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgraded Fedora]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/05/17/upgraded-fedora/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-17T05:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2008/05/17/upgraded-fedora</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just upgraded my laptop at work to Fedora 9, and I really like the new package manager, but otherwise am ambivalent about the upgrade. I recommend that upgraders wait a couple of weeks for some bugs to get ironed out first.</p>

<p>X just would not work at first&mdash;I had to use system-display-manager or system-display-configure (I&rsquo;m at home on my Mac) to correct the display drivers before that would work, and other services were breaking until I updated the system with the latest online only packages are restarted everything a couple of times.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
