<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Weekly Report | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/weekly-report/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-22T06:01:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacPorts / GNOME Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/03/17/macports-gnome-report/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-17T05:37:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/03/17/macports-gnome-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I managed to, within 3 days of <a href="http://www.gnome.org">GNOME</a> releasing version <a href="http://www.gnome.org/start/2.18">2.18.0</a>, get the entire current GNOME Platform into <a href="http://www.macports.org">MacPorts</a>. It actually took only a few hours work, and a day&rsquo;s waiting on compilers to get done.</p>

<p>I hope that getting the GNOME desktop into MacPorts is as painless as well.</p>

<p>Report 7</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacPorts / GNOME Weekly Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/01/28/macports-gnome-weekly-report-6/"/>
    <updated>2007-01-28T09:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/01/28/macports-gnome-weekly-report-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know, I know. This seems more like a quarterly report than a weekly report, but it is more that I took a sabbatical from port maintenance than that I have been lazy with this report.</p>

<p>Almost all of the ported <a href="http://www.gnome.org">GNOME</a> packages are now at current stable versions! The big blocker on this was (and remains) <a href="http://dbus.freedesktop.org">d-bus</a>. It builds correctly, the d-bus glib bindings build correctly, but d-bus does not work correctly. Try running the test suite (<strong>make check</strong>) after building it and you&rsquo;ll see the problem.</p>

<p>I am planning on reworking the TODOs section of the <a href="http://svn.macosforge.org/projects/macports/wiki/GNOME">MacPorts GNOME</a> page such that it is up-to-date and every TODO is listed as a ticket in the tracker.</p>

<p>Report 6</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacPorts / GNOME Weekly Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2006/10/15/macports-gnome-weekly-report-4/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-15T15:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2006/10/15/macports-gnome-weekly-report-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>GNOME has sound! (Actually ever since we ported gstreamer version 0.10.0+, GNOME has had working sound if the esd output was selected in the GNOME Preferences.) This weekend I ported gnome-audio. Although it has no dependencies, and nothing depends on it except the gnome-desktop-suite metaport, it does provide a default set of sounds for the GNOME desktop.</p>

<p>A significant portion of the GNOME desktop is now at the version 2.16.0 specifications, although there are a couple of ports, such as gnome-applets, that just refuse to upgrade from 2.12/2.14 versions. I&rsquo;m sure they can be made to at least build, but I haven&rsquo;t figured out how yet.</p>

<p>There a couple of <a href="http://svn.macosforge.org/projects/macports/query?status=new&amp;status=assigned&amp;status=reopened&amp;verbose=1&amp;keywords=%7EGNOME&amp;type=task&amp;order=priority">GNOME Tasks</a> that when completed, or possibly just partially completed, will improve the quality and maintainability of the GNOME ports. I am still adding tasks as I think of them and as I think of how to write them.</p>

<p>I have a <a href="http://homepage.mac.com/rhwood/macports/gnome.html">port status</a> table that lists all the ports in the GNOME desktop. If anyone wants to have a go at porting a package that is not ported, or at updating the outdated ports, please do so, <a href="https://svn.macosforge.org/projects/macports/newticket">file a ticket</a> with the port attached and assign it to <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#114;&#x68;&#x77;&#x6f;&#111;&#x64;&#x40;&#x6d;&#97;&#99;&#x70;&#x6f;&#x72;&#x74;&#115;&#x2e;&#111;&#114;&#103;&#x2e;">&#x72;&#104;&#119;&#111;&#x6f;&#100;&#64;&#x6d;&#97;&#x63;&#112;&#111;&#x72;&#x74;&#x73;&#x2e;&#111;&#114;&#103;&#46;</a> Please note that if a port is listed as Broken and the port can not be found, it means that I have started working on the port, but have not yet gotten it to build or run well enough to release it to the rest of the MacPorts community.</p>

<p>Report 4</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacPorts / GNOME Weekly Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2006/10/08/macports-gnome-weekly-report-3/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-08T09:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2006/10/08/macports-gnome-weekly-report-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>NSTR</strong></p>

<p>In military lingo, NSTR means Nothing Significant To Report and is a short-hand we use since we want to keep all communications over a tacticle radio (including computer-based communications) to under 15 seconds.</p>

<p>I copied a list of every port I had installed and then wiped out my installation and am reinstalling everything now, to ensure that everything is linked against the updated gettext port. I have the base GNOME installation installed, and two port fixes have come out of that, but no new improvements or upgrades have been done.</p>

<p>GNOME has released version 2.16.1, so I will be upgrading against packages in that list (or will be as soon as my base install is completed).</p>

<p>There is a new <a href="http://svn.macosforge.org/projects/macports/query?status=new&amp;status=assigned&amp;status=reopened&amp;verbose=1&amp;keywords=%7EGNOME&amp;type=task&amp;order=priority">GNOME-related Tasks</a> list for MacPorts, although as I am writing this the list is empty.</p>

<p>Report 3</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MacPorts / GNOME Weekly Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2006/10/01/macports-gnome-weekly-report-2/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-01T05:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2006/10/01/macports-gnome-weekly-report-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I began porting the GNOME desktop to version 2.16.0</p>

<p>I have been mostly porting libraries, not applications, so until I get the entire set in sync, it is possible that some applications will either fail to build or crash until the entire set is in sync.</p>

<p>Port <a href="http://dbus.freedesktop.org">dbus</a> has been reverted back to version 0.61 from 0.92 since dbus-glib can not build until some fundamental fixes are in on the dbus 0.9x ports. I have filed bugs with the upstream maintainer against this.</p>

<p>I thought that maybe I would have more to report, but it seems that perhaps I should hold off until next week, by which time, I hope to be more comfortable with the <a href="http://trac.edgewall.com/">Trac</a> ticket system that has replaced <a href="http://www.bugzilla.org">Bugzilla</a> on the MacPorts project.</p>

<p>Many things aren&rsquo;t working on my system due to the ongoing recovery from upgrading the gettext port and accidentally ripping out the older versions of that library.</p>

<p>Report 2</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
