<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Home | Shy Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/categories/home/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-21T06:47:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://rhwood.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Randall Wood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lonely Saxophones]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/03/30/lonely-saxophones/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-30T08:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2009/03/30/lonely-saxophones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember one summer at home&mdash;I think it was the summer of &lsquo;98&mdash;when a single lonely saxophone would play out over the roofs of the neighborhood in the evenings. It was one of the insanely beautiful moments that made Raleigh seem at so much more urbane and cosmopolitan than it seemed during the day.</p>

<p>In any event, yesterday was the first day of spring when doors and windows were flung open and people just stayed outdoors. Usually the music of balmy afternoons in my neighborhood is of a Mexican or Salvadorian flavor, and occasionally jazz or even classical music. Unfortunately this time it was abrasive sensationalist Hip-hop of the most banal and vulgar kind.</p>

<p>Somehow I managed to shutout the lyrics and think of that saxophone until the language was brought to my attention, and it kind of put a damper on the afternoon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redoing the Living Room]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/redoing-the-living-room/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-10T05:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/07/10/redoing-the-living-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend, we rearranged the common area (a combined living room/dining room) to not block off the living room as a separate room. It created the impression of significantly more space, gave us impetus to hang all of the artwork that Denis and Ingrid brought with them last time they visited, and makes the apartment feel more like a home and less like a transient barracks. There are <a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/randall.h.wood/RedoingTheLivingRoom">some photos</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dyson Animal]]></title>
    <link href="http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/05/30/dyson-animal/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-30T05:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://rhwood.github.io/blog/2007/05/30/dyson-animal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our old (and first) vacuum cleaner (a Eureka of some sort) died after 4 years.</p>

<p>We had bought our first vacuum cleaner at the Alexandria Target when we moved there, into our first apartment with carpeted floors.</p>

<p>We replaced it with a <a href="http://www.dyson.com/range/feature_frame.asp?model=DC17-ANIMAL&amp;sinavtype=menu">Dyson Animal</a> vacuum cleaner.</p>

<p>Chrysta was so happy with the Dyson that I thought of titling this post &ldquo;I married my mother-in-law.&rdquo; She has a number of very expensive vacuum cleaners and still buys more. It seems the real difference (in regards to vacuums) between Chrysta and her mother is that Chrysta let me place the old vacuum out beside the garbage dumpster where someone quickly took it away&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
